Chanusha Kaushal Gunarathne

147, Main Street, Buttala

MOBILE : +94 712774638 RESIDENCE : +94 552273332

E-MAIL : chanushakaushal1@gmail.com
LinkedIn : Chanusha Kaushal Gunarathne

in

PROFILE



Enthusiastic in exploring new learning horizons in Information Technology, which challenges my thinking and demands me to bring about a positive change in organizations. I am interested in acquiring knowledge and experience in the aspect of quality assurance. My career goal is to continuously grow in technical capacity whilst enriching management and leadership skills.

EDUCATION

BSc Special (Hons) – Information Technology Specialization – Information Technology Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology Feb 2017

Passed G.C.E Advanced Level Examination in Biological Science Stream

Aug 2010

Siridhamma College - Galle

WORK EXPERIENCE

Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd.

No: 752, Dr. Danister De Silva Mw, Dematagoda, Colombo 09

Associate Software Quality Assurance Engineer (11 Months)
Software Quality Assurance Engineer (1 Year & 1 Month)

March 2017 - Jan 2018 Feb 2018 - Present

CORE COMPETENCIES

Software Quality Assurance Sound Knowledge in Test Automation

Experience with manual testing Test Data Management

Web and mobile accessibility testing Good analyzing and analytical skills

Experiences with defect management process Good problem-solving skills

Knowledge of testing approaches and techniques Demonstrated skills in leadership

Experience with test designing & execution Teamwork

Experience with test metrices & analysis Software Development Life Cycle

Software Testing Life Cycle Photography

TECHNICAL SKILLS

QA Tools & Technologies	HP ALM Quality Center, Selenium Web Driver, TestNG, Soap UI,
	Sikuli (GUI Automation)
Other Tools & Technologies	Eclipse, NetBeans, GIT, Putty, FileZilla, MS Word, MS Excel
Languages	Java, HTML
DBMS & Tools	MSSQL, MYSQL, PL/SQL, Toad for Oracle

CERTIFICATION

Workshop on Test Automation Code Labs	Jan 2019
Certificate in Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)	Dec 2018
Certificate in Java Standard Edition Industrial Master (PVT) Ltd	April 2016
Certificate in Web designing WinSys Networks (PVT) Ltd	June 2015
Workshop on Network Cabling, CCTV Installation and PABX Intercom and Wireless Network Training Program WinSys Networks (PVT) Ltd	Dec 2014
Certificate in English Language British Council, Sri Lanka	Sep 2012

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Recommendation System for Online Social Network Recruiting – Research

Develop a LinkedIn based Applicant Recommendation system as a decision support system for Organizational recruitment process. System included trust model and progress model for recommend the applicant.

My English Teacher – Project

February 2015 – April 2015

Android application for English learning tool for Nursery children and absolute beginners. Featured with speech recognition, Text to speech, online assignments, Wikipedia search, YouTube search and user profile ranking features.

Gunarathne Stores Management System – Project

June 2014 – November 2014

Develop a java based standalone application for wholesale distribution company Gunarathne Stores to manage their business functions by using computerized approach.

Developed a website having capabilities of user registration and login and place orders with shopping cart.

INDUSTRIAL PROJECTS

Project	NYL LTC Agent Commission		
	Associate Engineer- QA Engineer- QA	April 2017 – March 2018	

Description

NYL LTC is in the process of migrating its current Long-term care agent commissions operations from LTCG to BASIS platform. LTCG is transferring the data that is needed for agent commission calculation to a new application called BASIS through feed files. Virtusa QA team is performing the testing on the new commissions platform to ensure that new commission platform cater the LTC business needs.

Responsibilities

- Planning, monitoring and control of the testing activities and tasks.
- Having an ownership of test data management (test data creation & test data loading).
- Maintain required domain knowledge within the team.
- Requirement Analysis and Test designing.
- Conducting peer reviews on the deliverables (Test Designs, Test Cases etc.).
- Participate in SQA reviews, requirement clarification and walk-through sessions.
- Test Execution (functional, and Regression testing).
- Back-end Test execution Database configurations and testing through Oracle SQL.
- Communicate with onsite team about release progress and production issues.
- Test case, test result and defect tracking in ALM.
- Collaborative working with development teams to get the defects fixed based on severity and priority.

Project	NYL LTC Middle Market Product	
	Engineer- QA Senior Engineer- QA	April 2018 – Dec 2018

Description

Middle Markets Product – MMP (also referred as Mass Markets Product) is the new LTC product from NYL catering to the needs to the needs of middle markets. BASIS needs to implement few requirements to meet these requirements.

Responsibilities

- Managing a team as the Team lead and reporting status update to both offshore and onsite teams.
- Responsible for Work allocating (Test cases creation, Test execution and defect verification) among the team.

- Review issues or clarifications identified by the team members within the projects and provide feedback and follow-up with QA lead/Developers and BA.
- Ramp up new team members by coming up with ramp up plans and Build the next level to ready for the current role.
- Having an ownership of test data management (test data creation & test data loading).
- Test Case tracking, defect reporting and defect management (HP Quality Center-ALM)
- Maintain the test metrices and analysis the test results.
- Maintain required domain knowledge within the team.
- Conducting peer reviews on the deliverables (Test Designs, Test Cases etc.).
- Participate in SQA reviews, requirement clarification and walk-through sessions.
- Test Execution (smoke, functional, Regression, Ad-hoc testing).
- Collaborative working with development teams to get the defects fixed based on severity and priority.

REFEREES

Mrs. Nipuni Udarika Mrs. Nadeesha Lakmini

Senior Consultant - QA Consultant - QA Virtusa Pvt.Ltd, Virtusa Pvt.Ltd,

752, Dr Danister De Silva Mawatha, 752, Dr Danister De Silva Mawatha,

Colombo 09, Sri Lanka. Colombo 09, Sri Lanka. Mobil: 071-6020025 Mobil: 077-1504468

I hereby declare that the above particulars are true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Chanusha Kaushal Gunarathne Date: 3/5/2019